Moses Gaines

gainesm.38@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Columbus, OH | (567) 525-9462

OBJECTIVE

Computer science graduate with 2 years of internship experience seeking a position to apply educational experience in programming language theory, computational complexity theory, and software development. Seeking to learn through practical, hands-on projects under expert guidance.

EDUCATION

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH

August 2020 – May 2024

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, GPA 3.716

Specialization: Software Engineering

Relevant Coursework: Object Oriented Programming (Java), Artificial Intelligence (Python), Algorithms, Data Structures, Software I & II (Java), Software and Web Applications, Databases (SQLite), Mobile App Development (Java)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Proficient in Java, Git, and Agile; Familiar with C, Python, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Django, HTML, CSS and SQL; Exposed to TypeScript

EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Seattle, WA

May 2023 – August 2023

Software Development Engineer Intern

- Designed and implemented an email notification suppression system to enhance user experience on spending platform
- Configured the frontend and backend mechanisms (utilizing Java and JS/ReactJS) to implement the system
- Communicated with customers and incorporated feedback to improve functionality and UX
- Successfully deployed notification suppression system to improve overall UX for the platform

Amazon, Findlay, OH (Remote)

June 2022 – August 2022

APP Software Development Engineer Intern

- Collaborated on design and implementation of an automated system to increase productivity of accountant reconciliation work
- Remodeled the existing accounting system to incorporate scheduling functionality, improving UX for accountants
- Presented the completed project to cross-functional stakeholders to ensure satisfaction
- Deployed completed system, reduced accountant workload and time expended

PROJECTS

Mobile App Development Project

- Description: A mobile application for android users that gives them the ability to create a login, create a group, add/remove people from the group, view their location, and create to-do/task lists shared within the group
- o Technologies Used: Java, FireBase, Google Maps

• Software Capstone Project

- Description: An application for OSU course administrators to create courses, find graders, and manage graders that are assigned automatically via the grader pairing algorithm
- o Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite, HTML, CSS, JavaScript